uniplaces.com 2013-12-14

# Privacy Policy — UniPlaces.com - Rent student accommodation online

**Uniplaces Limited Privacy Policy**

1.  INTRODUCTION

1.1  We are UNIPLACES LIMITED (referred to as " **we** ", “ **us** ” and “ **Uniplaces** ”) and we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy when you are visiting any website maintained by us including without limitation the website at www.uniplaces.com and our social networking pages and any application for mobile devices (together the “ **Website** ”), as we may publish and operate from time to time or communicating electronically with us, or attending an event organised by us (or on our behalf).

1.2  This policy, together with the Terms of Service (which can be found at the bottom of the Website at www.uniplaces.com) explains what types of personal and non-personal information we collect when you use the Website and the basis on which any personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. By disclosing your personal information to us by using the Website, speaking to us over the telephone or attending an event organised by us (or on our behalf) you consent to the collection, storage and processing of your personal information as stated in this policy.

1.3  Uniplaces uses the personal information we collect from you to provide our service to you. We will not rent, sell or share your personal information with any other company for its own marketing purposes without your consent except where mentioned in this policy.

1.4  For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the data controller is UNIPLACES LIMITED of c/o Buckworth Solicitors, 200 Aldersgate, London EC1A 4HDwhich is registered with the ICO with registered number: ZA000143

2.  What personal information do we collect?

2.1  When you register for the various services provided by the Website, update your registration details or otherwise use or register to use our services or agree to act as a Guarantor or emergency contract, certain of your personal information is collected by us. We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal information:

(a)  your name, address, email address, telephone number, fax number, username and password;

(b)  material submitted by you to us including without limitation answers to questions on surveys or registration forms;

(c)  payment information collected from you including without limitation credit and debit card numbers, financial institutions and credit card expiry dates; and

(d)  any other information from which you can be identified and which you may disclose to us at any time.

3.  How do we use personal information?

3.1  We may use your personal information for the following purposes:

(a)  to manage and administer the Website;

(b)  to improve your browsing experience by personalising the Website;

(c)  to assist in and administer the provision of our services to you, or if you are a guarantor, to administer your guarantee;

(d)  to send you newsletters and other relevant and targeted promotional communications;

(e)  to deal with enquiries, complaints and feedback from you and our service providers;

(f)  to provide third parties with statistical anonymised information about our users;

(g)  to investigate any suspected breaches of our Terms of Service or the breach of any other terms or conditions applicable to you.

3.2  In particular, during the process of booking a room, we only request information that is necessary to enable us to allocate your room in accordance with your needs and to contact you directly.

4.  When might we disclose personal information?

4.1  Except as set out below and to the extent required by any applicable law or governmental or judicial body, we will not disclose your personal information to any third party.4.2  We may pass your personal information to those of our employees and agents and those providing services on our behalf where we consider that it is necessary for the performance of our services to you.

4.3  We may also disclose your personal information to the accommodation provider who is providing your room.

4.4  We may provide general statistical information about our users including, sales patterns, traffic volumes and related matters to reputable third parties but these details will not include information personally identifying you.

4.5  We may disclose your personal information to the police, regulatory bodies or legal advisers in connection with any alleged criminal offence or suspected breach of our Terms of Service and/or the breach of other terms and conditions otherwise relating to you or otherwise where required by law. We will co-operate with law enforcement agencies and will comply with any court order requesting or directing us to disclose the identity of (or personal information relating to) any user breaching our Terms of Service and/or the breach of other terms and conditions otherwise relating to such user or otherwise for the prevention or detection of crime or the apprehension or prosecution of offenders.

5.  Our use of cookies and web beacons

5.1  Cookies are text files stored, either on a temporary or persistent basis on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies are used for authenticating, session tracking and maintaining specific information about the use and users of the Website.

5.2  The data collected by cookies is anonymous. You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer's hard drive by searching for files with "cookie" in it and deleting them. In addition, if you want to stop cookies from being stored on your computer, you can edit your browser settings so that cookies are blocked. Unfortunately, if you block cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Website. For more information about cookies, please visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)5.3  Web beacons consist of a small string of software code that represents a graphic image request on a page or email. There may or may not be a visible graphic image associated with the web beacon and often the image is designed to blend into the background of a page or email. Web beacons can be used for many purposes - including site traffic reporting, unique visitor counts, advertising auditing and reporting, and personalization. Web beacons used by the Website collect only anonymous data.

5.4  In order to improve the Website and the services we offer you, we may use (temporary and persistent) cookies, authorized third parties cookies, web beacons and/or other technologies to collect non-personally identifiable data. This non-personally identifiable data helps us to track browsing behavior, to create specific or tailor-made offers or advertisements, and to monitor and record the visits and use of the Website.5.5  In order to understand how people use the Website and for marketing analysis and quality improvement purposes, we (and/or third party service providers) may collect, record, process and use on an anonymous basis certain information (including the total number of transactions, viewed pages, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp information and details like the number and location of mouse clicks on a given page, mouse movements, scrolling activity and the search words you use while being on and using the Website.

5.6  If you register with us or if you continue to use the Website, you agree to our use of cookies.

6.  Where we store your personal information 

6.1  The personal information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

6.2  All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers.

6.3  We take the security of your personal information very seriously. In particular we use all reasonable endeavours to ensure that appropriate security measures are in place to protect your personal information. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and so we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted through the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

7.  Links to Third Party websites

7.1  The Website may include links to third party websites. We are not responsible for the content of third party websites. Please ensure that prior to using any such website, you have read and understood its privacy policy and terms of service. These documents will govern your rights and obligations when using the relevant third party website.

8.  Your rights

The Act gives you the right to ask us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your personal information) if we intend to use your personal information for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your personal information.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at info@uniplaces.com.

9.  Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

10.  Changes to our privacy policy

We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy. Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

11.  Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to info@uniplaces.com.
